Nationality:INDIAN | Phone:+919952216140 | Email:vivek.k@wipro.com|DOB:26-01-1991

#### Software Engineer,

With 8+ years of work experience in Information Technology on Supply Chain Management Corporate Banking, Investment Banking. I come with core expertise on server side development which includes Java web applications and Restful Web Services.

#### Quick Summary of my career

- Experience in Java 1.8, Spring, Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA, MicroServices with Spring Cloud, Restful WebServices and databases (SQL, Oracle and MYSQL).
- Progressive experience in analysis, development and implementation of Software applications using Java Technologies, ability to adapt new technologies.
- Ability to communicate with people in effective manner and have the motivation to take independent responsibility as well as ability to contribute and be a productive team player.

#### **Technical Skills**

➤ Languages - Core Java(V1.7, 1.8), JS

> Frameworks & Technology - Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA, Micro services, Junit

➤ Web Services - Restful Web services

➤ Tools - Eclipse, STS, Jenkins, Putty, WinSCP, JIRA, GIT, Swagger, Postman,

➤ DB/Servers - Oracle DB, SQL DB, Dynamo DB, Tomcat, Web logic

#### **Professional Experience**

Total IT Experience	8+ Years	Current Designatio n	Sr. Software Developer
Current Employer [May 2023- Present]	Wipro Techn	ologies pvt ltd, Chenna	i.
Previous Employer [May 2019 – Dec 2022]	Capgemini Pvt ltd.(Client: Standard Chartered Bank), Chennai.		
Previous Employment [May 2017 –Feb 2019]	Datazoic Ma ltd.), Chennai.	achines pvt ltd.(Consult	ant : Tquanta Technologies pvt
Previous Employment [Jun 2015 –Apr 2017]	Nova Techs	et Pvt ltd, Chennai.	

### **Current Project Details**

Project	Conditional Rebate Tool	
Duration	Feb 2024 – June 2024	
Role	Sr. Software Developer	
Technologies	Java 1.8, Spring Boot, Microservices, JPA, Oracle DB	
Team Size	10	
Company	Wipro Technologies Pvt ltd. ( Apple, Chennai )	
Users	Apple team	
<b>Brief Description of the</b>	About the Project :	
Roles and Responsibilities	Working as a Backend Java Developer. Conditional Rebate Tool	
	is an internal tool used in Apple where we can create proposals using	
	refresh Opportunities based on tradein values and product Mapping.	
	Roles and Responsibilities:	
	➤ Involved in developing Spring Boot Rest-API Webservices.	
	➤ Worked on complete Refresh the base module	
	backend APIs.	
	Implemented APIs for uploading Bulk Tradein Values for Products, Product Mapping using Excel.	
	<ul> <li>Worked on creating Refresh Opportunities, Find RO based on Tradein Value and Product Mapping, Find Product Mapping, Audit Trail in any modification in product mapping pages APIs.</li> </ul>	
	Worked on creating proposals and proposal PDF download APIs.	
	Worked on Dashboard APIs for showing products based on sold Qty, Region, countries, Traders and price.	
	➤ Worked on SQL queries, triggers and stored procedures.	

## **Previous Project Details**

Project	Privacy Management
Duration	Aug 2023 – Jan 2024
Role	Sr. Software Developer
Technologies	Java 1.8, Spring Boot, Microservices, JPA, MYSQL and Dynamo DB
Team Size	10
Company	Wipro Technologies Pvt ltd. ( Apple, Chennai )
Users	Apple team

Brief Description of the Roles and Responsibilities	About the Project:  Working as a Backend Java Developer. Privacy Management is an internal tool used in Apple.	
	Roles and Responsibilities :	
	Involved in developing Spring Boot Rest-API Webservices.	
	Involved in Analysing, Planning, developing, implementing requirements gathered from Business and Architecture team.	
	Worked on Reporting functionality where we can generate Excels based on Json data.	
	Implemented Filter Functionality APIs where user can capture filtered results in Excel.	
	Involved in resolving Production issues, sprint planning and daily scrum meeting.	

Project	Corporate Banking and CC Avenues Integration	
Duration	May 2019 – Dec 2022	
Role	Sr. Software Consultant	
Technologies	Java, Rest API, Hibernate, Oracle DB, Junit	
Team Size	35-40	
Company	Capgemini Pvt ltd. ( Client Location SCB, Chennai )	
Users	Several Countries Wherever SCB Branches are available	
<b>Brief Description of the</b>	About the Project :	
Roles and Responsibilities	Have worked in Out Bond and Inbound Corporate Banking project for	
	3+ years as Senior Developer for implementations of different project	
	requirement /enhancements/Issue fixes.	
	Developed a Restful API for integrating CC Avenues with SCB	
	Application. Worked on implementation and support for the entire	
	project.	
	Having development experience on Microservice Architecture using	
	technologies Java, Spring Boot, Restful API, Spring Data JPA for	
	Migrations Project	
	Roles and Responsibilities:	
	<ul> <li>Development, Enhancements, Implementations</li> </ul>	
	➤ Release planning, co-ordination and support	
	Communicate with onsite clients to get	
	baseline requirements for enhancement	
	projects	
	<ul><li>Production L3 Support</li></ul>	

Project	Prism and Trader App
Duration	May 2017 – Feb 2019
Role	Software Engineer
Technologies	Java, Rest API, SQL DB, Javascript, Groovy
Team Size	9 (6 Dev, 1 QA, 1BA,1 Manager)
Company	Datazoic Machines pvt ltd, Chennai.
Users	Cantor Fitzgerald, Oppenheimer & Co, Cowen, USA.

# **Brief Description of the Roles and Responsibilities**

#### **About the Project:**

Prism is a predictive analytics platform & caters to the needs of Research Analysts, Sales, Corporate Access teams, Investment Bankers, Wealth Management professionals etc.

Various products with in Prism umbrella provides comprehensive coverage to premier global financial services firm and is recognized for its analytical capability & strength in the area of Sales & Trading, Equity, Fixed income and Investment banking.

Have worked in Prism and Trader App projects for 1.5+ years as Senior Developer for implementations of different project requirement /enhancements/Issue fixes.

Having development experience on legacy technologies like Core Java, JSP, Java Script, Servlet, JDBC, SQL stored procedures.

#### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Development, Enhancements, Implementations.
- Worked with Fix Transaction, kestrel queue to receive data in trader app.
- Ensure the Overall quality of deliverables, and fixing/resolving the defects/issues proactively, by taking the leadership of the modules independently.
- Written Complex SQL queries and Stored procedures.
- Interacting with client in weekly meetings to resolve any server related issues, requirements and other challenges.

Project	DigiEdit
Duration	June 2015 – April 2017
Role	Software Trainee
Technologies	Core Java, SQL, Perl, VB, XML
Team Size	6
Company	Nova techset pvt ltd, Chennai.
Users	Taylor & Francis, Elsevier, Wiley

## Brief Description of the Roles and Responsibilities

#### **About the Project :**

DigiEdit is an document editing tool. Used for document conversion, manipulation and storing in the databases. End to end file processing including image, equation conversion. Also used for Image and Text Extraction.

Having development experience on technologies like Core Java, JDBC, SQL, Perl and VB

#### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Development, Enhancements, Implementations.
- Worked with end to end file movement and bug fixing.
- Ensure the Overall quality of deliverables, and fixing/resolving the defects/issues proactively, by taking the leadership of the modules independently.
- Basic knowledge of Perl, VB.
- Production support.

#### **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION**

- B.E (76%) SNS College of Engineering (Anna University)-TamilNadu.
- 12<sup>th</sup> (88%)– Adharsh Vidhyalaya Matric School, State Board of TamilNadu.
- 10<sup>th</sup> (84%)– Little Flower matric School, State Board of TamilNadu.

I hereby declare that the above information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge

Place: Chennai.

Date:

(K.VIVEK)